American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIb. 1807-1825 APS.Archives.IIb APS.Archives.IIb
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Report of committee on the insects sent in by Louis Vanuxem, May 7, 1824; 7-1/2x4-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: Thomas Say and R. Harlan. 2p.,end. Cf. Minutes, p.529.
  - Letter to [the A.P.S.], May 7, 1824; 10x8; Société de géographie (France)
    Paris, Printed L. 4p. In French. Concerning the aims of the society.
  - Report of the committee to whom was referred the memoir accompanying the tables of meteorlogical observations made at Washington, D.C., from April 17, 1823 to April 18, 1824, by Jules de Wallenstein., 1824 May 21; American Philosophical Society.
    Committee report on the memoir accompanying the table of meteorological observations made at Washington D.C., from April 17, 1823 to April 18, 1824. by Jules de Wallenstein.
  - D[avid] Hosack to John Vaughan, June 3, 1824; 7 13/16" x 9 11/16"; Hosack, David, 1769-1835
    New York, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Acknowledges the receipt of [A.P.S.] Catalogue. Presents several books to the Society.
  - J. E. DeKay to John Vaughan, June 9, 1824; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; DeKay, J. E.
    New York, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Forwards Collections. III, of the Historical Society of New York to A.P.S.
  - J. E. DeKay to John Vaughan, June 9, 1824; 4" x 4 1/4"; DeKay, J. E.
    New York, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Presents four numbers of Annals of the Lyceum of Natural History of New York to the American Philosophical Society.
  - Jose Maria Salazar to John Vaughan, June 10, 1824; 8" x 10"; Salazar, José María, 1785-1828
    Secretary of the A.P.S., Philadelphia, 2 pp. and endorsement. L.S. Encloses ms. of words and phrases of the language of the Darien Indians. Work of members of Museum of Natural Sciences at Bogota.
  - [John D.] Godman to John Vaughan, June 18, 1824; 7 13/16" x 9 7/8"; Godman, John D. ( John Davidson), 1794-1830
    ----, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L. in 3d. per. Requests permission to examine the collection of mastodon bones in the cabinet of the A.P.S.
  - George Ord to Jose Maria Salazar, June 18, 1824; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Ord, George, 1781-1866
    Philadelphia, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges the receipt of a manuscript collection of words and phrases of the Darien Indians.
  - Letter to [George] Ord, June 25, 1824; 7-1/2x4-1/2; Horsfield, Thomas, 1773-1859
    London, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Forwards publication.
  - James Kitchen, Jr., to John Vaughan, July 8, 1824; 7 7/8" x 8 1/8"; Kitchen, James, Jr.
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Submits list of pamphlets brought from Paris.
  - Letter to J. Vaughan, July 8, 1824; 7 1/2" x 9 1/2"; Van Rensselaer, Jeremiah, 1793-1871
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Sends a copy of his Essay on salt for the A.P.S.
  - Letter to the President of the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, July 19, 1824; 9-1/2x8; Académie des sciences (France)
    Paris, L.S: Cuvier. 1p.and add., end. In French. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to George Ord, secretary of A.P.S., July 23, 1824; 6 1/2" x 8 1/2"; DuPonceau, John W. chev. de, -1835
    Fontenay-Le-Comte (Vendée) A.L.S. 2p. and end. Acknowledges receipt of diploma of membership.
  - Letter to Mrs. Anne Patterson, July 26, 1824; 8" x 10"; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, L.S: Wm. Tilghman, Jn. Vaughan, N. Chapman, Comm. of the Am. Phil. Soc. 1p. and add. Contains the seal of the secretary of the A.P.S. Expression of sympathy of the death of her husband, Robert Patterson, late president of the Society. See Minutes, July 23, 1824, for reference to the letter. Text of letter appears to be in Tilghman's hand. Presented by H.C. Tilghman Hough, Nov. 1937.
  - A. Girard to John Vaughan, July 31, 1824; 8" x 9 3/4"; Girard, A.
    New York, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. With regard to a case of books marked "J.V." that have arrived in New York.
  - W[illia]m Laurence to G[eorge] Ord, Secretary of the A.P.S., August 4, 1824; 7 3/8" x 9 1/16"; Laurence, William
    London, 2 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the A.P.S.; presents a new edition of a surgical work, "which I have just published."
  - W[illia]m Lawrence to R[ichard] Harlan, August 8, 1824; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Lawrence, William
    London, 3 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Mr. Ord has notified him of election to A.P.S. which he has acknowledged. Presents surgical work.
  - W[illia]m Vaughan to John Vaughan, September 6, 1824; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Forwards to the A.P.S.: Francis Baily's memoir "on a new method of determining the longitude... "
  - Letter to [Joseph von] Hammer[-Purgstall], Sept. 16, 1824; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Resumé of A.L. 1p. (see APS. Historical...committee. Letterbooks, vol. 3, p. 29.) Forwards publications.
  - Letter to General Lafayette, Oct. 1, 1824; 12-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society
    L.S.: Peter S.DuPonceau 1p. Testimonial presented at reception held by APS in his honor; Oct. 1, 1824. Refers to Franklin and Jefferson. Reproduced: J.B.Nolan. "Lafayette and the APS" - APS Proceedings,v.73,p.117.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, October 3, 1824; 7 1/2" x 9", 8 1/2" X 12"; Rafn, Carl Christian, 1795-1864
    Copenhagen, A.L.S. 3p. and end. Enclosure - 3p. and end. In Latin. Solicits subscription to a proposed publication of Islandic historical monuments by the Islandic society of antiquarians. Encloses an index of the narratives of the voyages in the 11th century to Vinland. Accompanied by English translation in hand of Nicholas Collin (?), 4p. See A.P.S. Minutes,Feb. 4,1825.
  - E. J. Correa de Serra to George Ord, October 10, 1824; 7 3/4" x 10"; Correa de Serra, E. J.
    Secretary of the A.P.S., Paris, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges sympathy extended by the Society upon the death of his father, Joseph Correa de Serra. Copy of letter printed in APS Trans. v.45, Part 2, pp.190.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Oct. 10, 1824; 10x8; Corrêa da Serra, Edward Joseph, 1803-
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p. Concerning the death of his father. Forwards resume of his life.
  - Report of committee on paper by Troost on yenite, November 5, 1824; 5x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: R.M.Patterson, Isaiah Lukens and William Hembel, jr. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p,533. Printed: APS Transactions, n.s. II, 478 ff.
  - Letter to [the American philosophical society], Nov. 25, 1824; 13x8; Plantou, Anthony
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 4p.,end. (see Ms. Comm.to the APS. Mechanics, Machinery, Eng., etc., no. 52.) Concerning the safer generation of steam without a boiler. Cf. Minutes, p.534, 535.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Nov. 26, 1824; 8" x 10"; Literary and Philosophical Society of Manchester
    [Manchester], Printed form filled in in ms.S: Peter Clara, John Ja[me]s Taylor, secretaries. 1p. and add. end. Acknowledges Catalogue of A.P.S. Library. Cf. Minutes of July 15, 1825.
  - Edward Florence Rivinus to John Vaughan, November 27, 1824; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Rivinus, Edward Florens, 1802-1873
    Secretary to the A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents to the A.P.S.: a copy of his Historical and statistical description of the north of England.
  - Report of committee on A.Plantou's paper on the generation of steam, Dec. 17, 1824; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, D.S.: R.M. Patterson, William Hembel,jr and Isaiah Lukens. 3p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.535.
  - Letter to W[illia]m H. Keating, secretary of the A.P.S., January 6, 1825; 8" x 10"; Kruzenshtern, Ivan Fedorovich, 1770-1846
    St. Petersburg, A.L.S. 3p. and end. 2 copies Acknowledges letter sent by M. de Wallenstein advising him of his election to membership in the A.P.S. Sends a copy of a collection of charts of the Pacific ocean. Cf. Minutes - May 6, 1825.
  - Tho[mas] Horsfield to George Ord, January 17, 1825; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Horsfield, Thomas, 1773-1859
    Secretary of the A.P.S., London, 2pp., address and endorsement. Forwards his Zoölogical Researches in Java, VIII, to the A.P.S.
  - Report of the committee appointed for the purpose of investing the funds of the Society... [Philadelphia], January 20, 1825; 7 15/16" x 9 15/16"; American Philosophical Society
    1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: Clement C. Biddle, G[eorge] Ord, R[obert] M. Patterson. Have invested $1049.74 in a certificate of U. S. 4 1/2 p.c. stock of 1824.
  - J[ohn] J. Bigsby to George Ord, January 22, 1825; 7 15/16" x 9 7/8"; Bigsby, John J. (John Jeremiah), 1792-1881
    Secretary of the A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - Letter to R[obert] M[askell] Patterson, 1825 February 1; Royal Horticultural Society (Great Britain)
    Acknowledgment of the gift by the A.P.S. of it Library Catalog sent to the Royal Horticultural Society.
  - Report of the committee to whom was referred the communication made... by Commodore Barron on... ventilating ships of war, February 4, 1825; 7 3/4" x 12 5/8"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 9 pp. and endorsement. D.S.: R[obert] M. Patterson, William] Jones, William Hembel, Jr. Recommend that the paper be laid on the table.
  - Alex[ande]r Pearson to George Ord, February 7, 1825; 8" x 10"; Pearson, Alexander
    Secretary of the A.P.S., Canton, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 7, 1825; 8" x 10"; Royal Institution of Great Britain
    London, Printed form filled in in ms.S: J[ohn] Guillemard, Secretary. 1p. and end. Acknowledges Catalogue of A.P.S.
  - Letter to The American philosophical society, Feb. 8, 1825; 7" x 9"; London Institution
    [London], Printed form filled in in ms.S: W[illia]m Maltby, Principal librarian. 1p.and end. Expresses thanks of the Managers of the London institution for the Catalogue of the A.P.S. Library.
  - Report of committee on an air pump, Feb. 18, 1825; 8x5-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: R.M. Patterson and Isaiah Lukens. 2p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.536.
  - Letter to W[illiam] H. Keating, 1825 February 21, 23; Lyceum of Natural History (New York)
  - Report of committee on S.H.Long's new method of transferring boats of burden, March 4, 1825; 12-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, D.S.: R.M.Patterson,William Strickland, and Isaiah Lukens. 4p.,end. Cf. Minutes, p.540.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., March 4, 1825; 9x7-1/2; Literary and Philosophical Society of Manchester
    Manchester, L.S.: Peter Clare and John Jas. Tayler. 1p. and add., end. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 4, 1825; 8" x 9 3/4"; Temminck, C. J. (Coenraad Jacob), 1778-1858
    Amsterdam, A.L.S. 2p. and end. In French. Acknowledges election to membership cf. Minutes - May 20, 1825.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American philosophical society, March 11, 1825; 8x5; Geological Society of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Thomas Webster. 1p.and end. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to R. M. Pattison [sic], March 25, 1825; 9x7-1/2; Royal Horticultural Society (Great Britain)
  - Letter to Robert Patterson, March, 1825; 10x8; Lobstein, J. F. Daniel (Johann Friedrich Daniel), 1777-1840
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Forwards publication.
  - Concerning fossils and a new genus Glires, April 1, 1825; 10x8; Harlan, Richard, 1796-1843
    [read] D. 11p.and end. (see Ms.comm. to the APS. Natural history, vol. 2, nos. 65-66.) Cf. Minutes, p.541.
  - Letter to Reuben G. Beasley, La Havre, April 5, 1825; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Resumé of A.L. 1p. (see APS. Historical...committee. Letterbooks, vol. 3, p. 34.) Forwards publications. Mentions Lafayette.
  - Letter to the [A.P.S.], April 10, 1825; 10-1/2x8; Société de geógraphie (France)
  - James Barron to James Mease, April 11, 1825; 7 3/4" x 10 1/8"; Barron, James, 1769-1851
    Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Sends to A.P.S. a model of Charles D. Brodie's plan for repairing ships under the surface of the water. See Minutes, April 15, 1825, in Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 542.
  - Letter to Charles N. Bancker, April 15, 1825; 9 3/4" x 8"; American Philosophical Society
    Hall of the...society, A.L.S: Willm. H. Keating, sec. 1p. and add., end. Notification of election to membership. Presented by Mrs. Bernard R. Boak, May 1952.
  - Letter to [John Vaughan?], April 19, 1825; 8x5; Académie royale des beaux-arts de Bruxelles
    Anvers, A.L.S.: Chevalier de Kirckhoff. 1p. and end. In French. forwards publication.
  - Letter to W[illiam] H[ypolitus] Keating, Philadelphia, April 19, 1825; 10x8; Royal Astronomical Society
    London, A.L.S.: J.F.W.Herschel. 1p.and add.,end. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to Will[iam] H. Keating, secretary of the A.P.S., April 22, 1825; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Réal, P. F. (Pierre François), comte, 1757-1834
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. and add. In French. Acknowledges election to membership. Cf. Minutes - May 6, 1825.
  - Daniel W. Coxe to John Vaughan, April 25, 1825; 7 15/16" x 9 15/16"; Coxe, Daniel W. (Daniel William), 1769-1852
    [Philadelphia], 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents to the A.P.S.: the Abbé Rozier's dictionary on agriculture, in 12 vols.
  - Letter to the A.P.S., April 30, 1825; 10x8; Société de géographie (France)
    Paris, L.S.: Barbié du Bocage. 2p. and end. In French. Introductory letter.
  - Letter to J[ames] Mease, May 4, 1825; 10x8; Humphreys, Samuel, 1778-1846
    A.L.S. 1p. Cost of repairing a ship. Used as basis for APS report of committee; May 26, 1825.
  - Report of committee on C.D.Brodie's apparatus entered for the Magellanic premium, May 6, 1825; 9-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: James Mease and William Hembel, jr. 3p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.542. See letter from Sam. Humphreys to J.Mease; May 4, 1825.
  - Letter to the President of the APS, Philadelphia, May 20, 1825; 10x8; New Hampshire Historical Society
    Portsmouth, L.S.: Nath. Adams. 1p. and add., end. Forwards publication.
  - Peter S. DuPonceau to John Vaughan, June 11, 1825; 7 13/16" x 9 7/8"; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Is unable to find either of the MSS. on the North Carolina line. Thinks that Mr. Vaughan must have lent them to some member.
  - W[illiam] Short to J[ohn] Vaughan, June 11, 1825; 7 7/8" x 9 15/16"; Short, William, 1759-1849
    Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Offers to deposit his private library with the A.P.S., for the use of its members.
  - Jer. Van Rensselaer to J[ohn] Vaughan, June 15, 1825; 7 3/8" x 9"; Van Rensselaer, Jeremiah, 1793-1871
    New York, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. The Lyceum of Natural History forwards cast of jaw of megatherium to A.P.S. See Minutes, August 19, 1825, in Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 544.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, June19/July 7, 1825; 10x8; Middleton, Henry, 1770-1846
    L. Extract. 1p. and end. Forwards publications by krusenstern.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, June 22, 1825; 10x8; Societas Regia Scientiarum Upsaliensis
    Upsala, L.S.: Pehr Fab. Aurivillius. 1p. and end. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to Franklin Bache, 1825 June 29; Short, William, 1759-1849
    Letter to Franiklin Bache, regarding the deposit of William Short's library with the A.P.S..
  - Letter to Levett Harris, 1825 July 3/15; Romanoff, Nicolas, comte de
    Extract of a letter from the Comte de Roamnoff, Chancellor of the Empire of Russia.
  - Anne Harris to Robert Patterson, July 21, 1825; 7 7/8" x 9 5/8"; Harris, Anne
    Bellefonte, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Forwards several copies of her work, the Alphabet of Thought.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, July 27, 1825; 10x8; Smyth, George W.
    L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Forwards Jefferson's draft of the declaration. Film 199 Frame 283
  - Tho[ma]s Nuttall to John Vaughan, August 2, 1825; 7 7/8" x 9 5/8"; Nuttall, Thomas, 1786-1859
    Cambridge, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. With regard to an unfinished communication.
  - Letter to the A.P.S., Sept. 18, 1825; 10x8; Huygens, Chevalier
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. and end. In French. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, 1825 October 6; Walker, G.H.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Vaughan, Oct. 11, 1825; 8x5; Pedersen, Peder, 1774-1851
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. Forwarded publications to the Royal Danish society of sciences. Donates material to the APS.
  - Charles Smith to Peter S. DuPonceau, October 13, 1825; 7 3/4" x 10 1/8"; Smith, Charles, 1765-1836
    Chambersburg, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Donates some Indian relics and fossil shells to the A.P.S.
  - W[illia]m J. Macneven to Peter [S.] DuPonceau, October 22, 1825; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Macneven, William James, 1763-1841
    New York, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Requests the return of his paper, which was not published in the A.P.S. Transactions.
  - Letter to George Ord, secretary of the A.P.S., October 23, 1825; 8" x 10"; Miot de Melito, André François comte, 1762-1841
    Point Breeze, A.L.S. 2p. and add. In French. Acknowledges election to membership. Cf. Minutes - Nov. 4,1825.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Oct. 29, 1825; 10x8; Library of congress
    Washington, L.S.: Geo.Watterston. 1p.and end. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Nov. 4, 1825; 7-1/2x5; Buchet-Martigny
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. In French. Forwards publications.
  - Daniel Brent to John Vaughan, November 15, 1825; 8" x 9 15/16"; Brent, Daniel, 1774-1841
    Secretary of the A.P.S., Department of State, Washington, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Forwards to the A.P.S.: documents of 17th. Congress, 2d. session, and 18th. Congress, 1st. session.
  - Philip Tidyman to G[eorge] Ord, November 19, 1825; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Tidyman, Philip
    Secretary of the A.P.S., Charleston, South Carolina, 1 p., address and endorsements. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - Letter to [John] Vaughan, Philadelphia, Nov. 27, 1825; 9-1/2 x 8; Struve, Heinrich Christian Gottfried von, 1772-1851
    Wurtenburg, A.L.S. 1p. and end. In French. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Nov. 30, 1825; 8" x 9 3/4"; Van Rensselaer, Jeremiah, 1793-1871
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Sends a copy of his Lectures on geology for the A.P.S. Cf. Minutes Dec. 16, 1825.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Vaughan, Philadelphia, Nov. 30, 1825; 10x8; New York Academy of Sciences
    New York, A.L.S.: Jer. Van Rensselaer. 1p.and end. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Dec. 26, 1825; 10x8; Library of congress
    Washington, A.L.S.: M. Dickerson. 1p.and end. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to R. M. Pattison[sic], Dec. 27, 1825; 9-1/2 x 7-1/2; Royal Horticultural Society (Great Britain)
  - Report of committee on William Murrat's demonstration of Newton's binomial system, Dec. 16, 1825; 8x6-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: F. Nichols and E. Nulty. 1p.and end. Cf. minutes, p.548.
  - Letter to, [1825]; Silva Lisboa, Jose da
    Acknowledges with appreciation his receipt of a diploma of membership in the American Philosophical Society. He slao sends a copy of his work Constituicao moral.
  - NOT FOUND
    - Concerning a vaccination, Feb. 19, 1808; 12x7-1/2; Buchanan, George, 1763-1808
      D. 1p.and end. (see Ms. Comm.to the APS. Medicine, anatomy and physiology, no. 23.) Cf. Minutes, p.404.
    - Concerning hot springs at the Cape of Good Hope, May 3, 1808; 10x8; Elmslie, John
      [ca.]. APS. Natural philosophy, vol. 1, no. 29.) Enclosed originally in letter from Elmslie to Griffiths; May 3, 1808.
    - Specific gravity of a meteoric stone, April 8, 1808; 8x6; Patterson, Robert, 1743-1824
      A.D.S. 1p. (see Ms.comm.to the APS. Natural philosophy, vol. 1, no. 55)
    - Letter to ----, March 28, 1808; 10x8; Kirk, Timothy
      Little Falls, Mass., (?). A.L.S. 2p.,end. (see Ms. Comm. to the APS. Mechanics, Machinery, Eng., etc., no. 33.) Concerning a machine for ascertaining longitude. Cf. Minutes, p.404.
    - Concerning meteoric stones, June 10, 1808; 10x8; Hassler, F. R. (Ferdinand Rudolph), 1770-1843
      A.D.S. 11p.and end. (see Ms. comm.to the APS. Natural philosophy, vol. 1, no. 57a) Enclosed originally in letter from Hassler to J.Vaughan; June 10, 1808. Cf. Minutes, pp.407,408.
    - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, June 10, 1808; 10x8; Hassler, F. R. (Ferdinand Rudolph), 1770-1843
      West Point, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. Enc. (see Ms.comm.to the APS. Natural philosophy, vol. 1, no. 57.) Forwards communication to the APS on meteoric stones. For enclosure, see: Hassler, Concerning meteoric stones; June 10, 1808.
    - Concerning the correct longitude of Washington, March 22, 1813; 13x8; Lambert, William
      Washington, A.D.S. 3p. (see Ms.comm.to the APS. Math.and astronomy, vol. 2, no. 84.) Printed: Trans., n.s., vol. I, 103ff.
    - Concerning geological formations, Jan. 8, 1809; 10x8; Williams, Robert, 1773-1836
      [ca.]. A.D. 24p.,end. (see Ms.comm. to the APS. Philology, literature, etc., vol. 1, no. 30.) Cf. Minutes, pp.412, 413. Enclosed originally in letter from R. Williams to the APS; Jan. 8, 1809.
    - Analysis of the Nicotina latifolia, Jan. 12, 1809; 7-1/2x6; Vauquelin, A., -1829
      D. 15p. Translated by D.B.Warden. (see Ms.comm.to the APS. Natural history, vol.1, no. 44.) Cf. Minutes, pp.417, 418. For report, see: APS. Report of committee...; March 16, 1810.
    - Cure for the croup, March 13, 1808; 5x7-1/2; Dean (?), Mrs.
      D. 1p.and end. (see Ms. Comm.to the APS. Medicine, anatomy and physiology, no. 35.)
    - Concerning the strength of timber on a bridge, May 1, 1808; 12-1/2x8; Gordon, E.
      [read] D.S. 2p.and add.: "John Vaughan", end. (see Ms.Comm.to the APS. Mechanics, Machinery, Eng.,etc.,no.32.) Cf. Minutes, pp.481, 487.
    - Letter to Dr. Griffith, Philadelphia, May 3, 1808; 10x8; Elmslie, John
      Cape Town, A.L.S. 2p.and add. Enc. (see Ms.comm.to the APS. Natural Philosophy, vol. 1, no. 56.) Sends article concerning the hot springs in the Cape of Good Hope. For enclosure, See: Elmslie. Concerning hot springs...; [May 3, 1808].
    - Letter to Thomas Jefferson, June 20, 1808; 8-1/2x7-1/2; Dabney, John Bass, 1766-1826
      Fayal, A.L.S. 7p. and end. (see Ms. Comm. to APS. Natural history, vol. 1, no. 41.) Volcano on St. George's Island.
    - Concerning a theorem for ascertaining a standard measure, 1808; 12x8; Bennet
      [received] D. 1p.and end. (see Ms.comm. to the APS. Math.and astronomy, vol. 2, no. 66.)
    - Letter to Tho[ma]s Jefferson, Chittenden, Vermont, May 28, 1808; 12-1/2x8; Harrison, Samuel
      Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p., end. Enc. (see Ms. Comm. to APS. Natural history, vol. 1, no. 32.) Natural history. On same sheet is letter from Samuel Peters to Harrison; Jan. 10, 1806.
    - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 8, 1809; 9-1/2x8; Williams, Robert, 1773-1836
      Raleigh, A.L.S. 2p.and end. Enc. (see Ms.comm.to the APS. Philology, literature, etc., vol. 1, no. 29.) Forwards memoir and asks to be made a member of the society. For enclosure, see: R.Williams. Concerning geological formations; [ca. Jan.8,1809].
    - Letter to [Thomas Jefferson], Jan. 20, 1809; 10-1/2x7-1/2; Creswell, Charles
      read A.L.S. 1p. and add. (mutilated), end. (see Ms. Comm. to APS. Natural history, vol. 1, no. 42a.) Geology.
    - Concerning Godon's observations to serve for a mineralogical map for the state of Maryland, Jan. 20, 1809; 10x8; Creswell, Charles
      D. 5p.and end. (see Ms. comm. to the APS. Natural history, vol. 1, no. 42.)